<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Prologue spoken by Mrs. Cook.</title>
            <author>Behn, Aphra, 1640-1689.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1684</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B01552</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing B1759A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide 839.m.22[25]</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99887025</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99887025</idno>
            <idno type="VID">181750</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B01552)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 181750)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; A2:2[25])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Prologue spoken by Mrs. Cook.</title>
                  <author>Behn, Aphra, 1640-1689.</author>
                  <author>Barrey, Mrs.</author>
                  <author>Cook, Mrs.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([2] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for Charles Tebroc,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London] :</pubPlace>
                  <date>[1684]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Attributed to Aphra Behn, cf. Wing.</note>
                  <note>Verse: "With that assurance we to day address ..."</note>
                  <note>On verso: Epilogue by a person of quality. Spoken by Mrs. Barrey.</note>
                  <note>Place and date of publication from Wing.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Prologues and epilogues --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>English poetry --  Early modern, 1500-1700 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>English drama --  Poetry --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-11</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-11</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-04</date>
            <label>Geremy Carnes</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-04</date>
            <label>Geremy Carnes</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="prologue">
            <pb facs="tcp:181750:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>PROLOGUE.</head>
            <byline>Spoken by M<hi rend="sup">rs.</hi> 
               <hi>Cook.</hi>
            </byline>
            <lg>
               <l>WIth that aſſurance we to day addreſs,</l>
               <l>As ſtandar'd Beauty certain of ſucceſs;</l>
               <l>With careleſs Pride at once they charm and vex,</l>
               <l>And ſcorn the little Cenſures of their Sex.</l>
               <l>Sure of the unregarded Spoil, deſpiſe</l>
               <l>The needleſs affectation of the Eyes.</l>
               <l>The ſoftening Languiſhment that faintly warms,</l>
               <l>But truſt alone to their reſiſtleſs Charms.</l>
               <l>So we ſecur'd by undiſputed Witt,</l>
               <l>Diſdain the damning Malice of the Pitt.</l>
               <l>Nor need falſe Art to ſet great Nature off,</l>
               <l>Or ſtudied tricks to force the Clap, and Laugh.</l>
               <l>Ye Wou'd-be Criticks you are all undone,</l>
               <l>For here's no Theam for you to work upon.</l>
               <l>Faith, ſeem to talk to <hi>Jenney,</hi> I adviſe;</l>
               <l>Of who, like who, and how Loves Markets riſe:</l>
               <l>Try theſe hard Times how to abate the Price,</l>
               <l>Tell her how Cheap were Damzels on the Ice!</l>
               <l>'Mongſt City Wives and Daughters that came there,</l>
               <l>How far a Guinny went at Blanket-fair!</l>
               <l>Thus you may find ſome good Excuſe for failing,</l>
               <l>Of your beloved Exerciſe of railing;</l>
               <l>That when friend cries; — how does the Play ſucceed,</l>
               <l>Damme — I hardly minded, what they did.</l>
               <l>We ſhall not your ill Nature pleaſe to Day,</l>
               <l>With ſome fond Scriblers new uncertain Play,</l>
               <l>Looſe as vain Youth, and tireſome as dull Age,</l>
               <l>Or Love and Honour, that o're-runs the Stage:</l>
               <l>Fam'd and ſubſtantial Authours give this Treat,</l>
               <l>And 'twill be ſolemn! Noble all, and Great!</l>
               <l>Witt! ſacred Witt, is all the buis'neſs here,</l>
               <l>Great <hi>Fletcher!</hi> and the Greater <hi>Rocheſter!</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Now name the hardy Man one fault dares find,</l>
               <l>In the vaſt work of two ſuch <hi>Heroe</hi>'s join'd.</l>
               <l>None but Young <hi>Strephon</hi>'s ſoft and powerfull Wit,</l>
               <l>Durſt undertake to mend what <hi>Fletcher</hi> writ.</l>
               <l>Different his Heav'nly Muſe, yet both agree,</l>
               <l>To make an everlaſting Harmony.</l>
               <l>Liſten ye Virgins to his Charming Song,</l>
               <l>Eternal Muſick dwelt upon his Tongue:</l>
               <l>The Gods of Love and Witt inſpir'd his Pen,</l>
               <l>And Love and Beauty was his Glorious Theam;</l>
               <l>Now Lady you may Celebrate his Name,</l>
               <l>Without a Scandal on your ſpotleſs Fame:</l>
               <l>With ſighs his dear lov'd Memory purſue,</l>
               <l>And pay his Wit, what to his Eyes was due,</l>
               <l>'Twill pleaſe his Ghoſt even in th' Elizian ſhade,</l>
               <l>To find his Power has ſuch a Conqueſt made.</l>
            </lg>
         </div>
         <div type="epilogue">
            <pb facs="tcp:181750:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>Epilogue</head>
            <byline>
               <hi>by a Perſon of Quality.</hi> Spoken by Mrs. <hi>Barrey.</hi>
            </byline>
            <lg>
               <l>'TIS well the Scene is laid remote from hence,</l>
               <l>'Twould bring in Queſtion elſe our Authors Senſe.</l>
               <l>Two Monſtrous, things produc'd for this our Age;</l>
               <l>And no where to be ſeen but on the Stage.</l>
               <l>A Woman Raviſht and a great man wiſe,</l>
               <l>Nay honeſt too without the Leaſt diſguiſe.</l>
               <l>Another Character deſerves great blame,</l>
               <l>A Cuckold daring to revenge his ſhame:</l>
               <lg type="triplet">
                  <l>A ſurly ill Natur'd Roman wanting wit,</l>
                  <l>Angry when all true Engliſhmen ſubmit,</l>
                  <l>Witneſs the tameneſs of the well Horn'd Pit.</l>
               </lg>
               <l>Tell me ye fair ones, pray now tell me why</l>
               <l>For ſuch a fault as this to bid me dye:</l>
               <lg type="triplet">
                  <l>Should Husbands thus Command and Wives obey,</l>
                  <l>'Twoul'd ſpoil our Audience for the next New Play,</l>
                  <l>Too many wanting who are here to day.</l>
               </lg>
               <l>For, I ſuppoſe if e're that happen to ye,</l>
               <l>'Twas force prevail'd you ſaid he would undoe ye.</l>
               <l>Strugling, cry'd out, but all alas in Vain,</l>
               <l>Like me you Underwent the Killing pain.</l>
               <l>Did you not pity me, Lament each groan,</l>
               <l>When left with the wild Emperor alone:</l>
               <l>I know your Tender Natures, did Partake,</l>
               <l>At leaſt in Thought you ſuffer'd for my ſake,</l>
               <l>And in my Rape bearing a friendly part,</l>
               <l>Each had her <hi>Valentinian</hi> in her Heart.</l>
            </lg>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>Printed for <hi>Charles Tebroe.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
